Software Engineer

PROFILE

I have been programming for 12 years, starting at the age of 12. I am interested in working with web development and software engineering, especially in a functional style. My especially broad knowledge and high adaptability is due to much of my experience coming from personal experience outside the industry. I am looking for full-time position in front-end or full-stack software engineering.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, THE NEW OFFICE, AUSTIN, TX JAN 2016 - DEC 2016 I worked on an Elm frontend and Elixir backend for data integration technology. This included doing a major pull request over many weeks to add support for connecting to a distributed MongoDB topology by conforming to their client specification.

SUPPORT ENGINEER, NODEJITSU; REMOTE MAR 2012 - APR 2013

I worked on Github pull requests for Node.js backend server software while providing technical support to other engineers using the hosting platform. Nodejitsu was bought out by GoDaddy a couple years ago.

FREELANCER, REMOTE 2013 - PRESENT

I have been freelancing on and off since I started programming. These projects include React, Redux and GraphQL full-stack websites, mobile and desktop cryptocurrency clients in Qt, and many other smaller projects in Unity 3D and other technologies.

EDUCATION

VIRGINIA TECH - COMPUTER SCIENCE, FALL 2018 (EXPECTED)

SKILLS

- Javascript/ES6 (babel, webpack, eslint)
- Node.js (express, hapi) and npm/yarn
- RxJS, lodash, luxon, GraphQL
- React, Redux, Next.js, styledcomponents
- HTML, CSS and SASS
- · Implementing mockup designs
- · Functional Programming

- Elixir with GenStage
- Distributed systems
- · Elm, Clojure, and Haskell
- · Git/Github and open source
- MongoDB, SQL
- · Fast learner, adaptable
- VS Code, Emacs
- · Linux, OS X and Windows